Good morning, please take a seat. How can I help you?
Well, I'm thinking of buying a new car and I'd like some advice.
Sure, yes. Had you got any particular make in mind?
I'm interested in a Lida. I've had one before and liked it
But I haven't really made up my mind.
Sure. We've got various models. Umm, right. What about the engine size? Any ideas?
The one I've got at the moment's a 1.2 litre engine
but I find it a bit slow on long journeys.
I'd like a bit more power this time, a 1.4 should do
I don't think I need a 1.6 or anything.
Right. Well I think the model you're looking at is the Max. Here's a picture.
Oh, yes, have you got one in?
Yes. I'll take you to have a look at it in a minute.
I'll just get a few more details. Er... Is there anything else to do with the engine?
What kind of gear change do you want? I presume you'd want a manual?
I'd want automatic. I've never driven a car with manual gears.
Right. Well now, here's the colour chart for the Max.
Have you given that any thought? This blue's very popular at the moment.
Yes, it is nice, I like blue. What's it called? 'Royal'?
Yes.
But actually, I think I prefer this lighter shade here-'Sky'.
Yes, that's popular too.
I think I'll go for that.
You might have to wait a week or so for that colour, but I assume that'd be OK?
Oh yes, fine.
Well, we can go outside and you can have a good look at one
and perhaps take it out.
But first, can I just ask you about finance?
The cash price is going to be somewhere in the region of seven and a half thousand.
How would you like to pay?
Are you in a position to pay cash, or would you need credit?
I'd like credit provided the terms are reasonable.
Well you can discuss that with my colleague in a moment; we have various arrangements.
And would you be interested in us taking your present car as part exchange?
Yes.
OK, fine. So I'll just need some details from you
and then we can do a valuation... Is that OK?
Fine, yes.
Could I have your full name?
Wendy Harries, that's H-A-R-R-I-E-S.
And is that Mrs... Miss... Ms...?
It's Doctor, actually.
Oh, right. And your address?
20 Green Banks.
Is that 'Green' spelled as in the colour?
Yes, that's right.
OK.
Ahon.
IS that O-L-T-O-N?
Not quite, it begins with an A, not an O.
Oh yes, that's in Hampshire isn't it?
That's right.
And do you know your postcode?
Yes. It's GU8 9EW Do you have a daytime phone number?
Well, I work at the hospital but it's a bit difficult to get hold of me.
I can give you a number just for messages
and then I'll get back to you when I can. Is that OK?
That's fine.
It's 0-7-9-8-2-5-7-6-4-3.
Fine. And about the car you have now, what make is it?
It's a Conti.
DO you know the year or the model name?
I think it's 1996, and it's called a Lion-like the animal.
Then it must be 1994, because they brought out the Fox after that.
Oh right, yes.
Mileage? Roughly?
I'm not sure. I know it's less than seventy thousand.
OK. What colour is it?
Right, and one last thing. What sort of condition would you say it's in?
I'd probably describe it as reasonable. Do you need to see it? It's parked outside.
Not at the moment, no. Perhaps you could call in one day next week...